[Uhtred] My name is Uhtred,
son of Uhtred.
I was born
an Aelderman of Northumbria,
the rightful heir
to Bebbanburg.
But fate decreed
I would be raised as a Dane.
That was my life.
Until my family was murdered.
[yelling]
Word was spread
that I was to blame.
A Saxon slave, he killed his
master, at a wedding party.
[Uhtred] And so Brida
and I fled to Wessex.
[crowd booing]
To Alfred, a man
who would become king.
Though not all agreed.
I am my father's heir!
[Uhtred]
I swore an oath to this King
An oath that lost me Brida,
and prevented me
from joining
my brother, Ragnar.
But destiny is all.
You don't deserve to marry.
That woman is a lady,
and you are a heathen.
You could bathe all day long
and you'd still
stink of pig shit.
Have you been watching me,
Odda the Boy?
Should I be marrying you?
Ten pieces of silver
for you to walk away.
Does your father
know you're here?
Eleven pieces.
How about my sword's weight,
in silver?
Nonsense.
Then I'll marry the girl,
and tonight, I'll plough her.
Why must you
talk of her like that?
Perhaps you'd like her
for yourself Odda.
You want her beneath you.
Am I right?
You are impossible to reason
with, everything is a game.
I hope for Mildrith's sake,
your time
on this earth is short.
You are not an Aelderman...
and never shall be.
[man commands horses]
[Uhtred] I wasn't allowed to
meet her. I haven't seen her.
It is the way.
I was unaware of her existence
until yesterday.
She will be plain and pious.
Oh, she'll be pious, alright.
If she was a leg-spreader,
Alfred would have
been on her by now.
Have you seen her?
A distance away.
Plain is a fair description.
-How much was the bride price?
-Thirty three pieces.
Which I have paid,
to her Godfather Odda,
and which I'll make sure
she receives.
I've made promises...
Revenge and such.
Why are you here? Do you know?
She brings land.
I'll become a Lord under Alfred.
I'll be able to make wealth;
gather men.
-Take back what's mine.
-All reasons enough.
Plain or not,
she serves her purpose.
The promises you have made
will stand.
Blood feuds last a lifetime.
What you do arseling,
is you keep living each day
until the last.
The priest has arrived, finally,
let's get this done.
You do not need
to get this done.
I will make a plea to Alfred.
She's here, praise God.
You should stand and look respectful,
if not entirely clean.
-How does she look?
-Terrified, I'll bet.
If you could be brief
with the ceremony Father Beocca,
I would be grateful.
I have business with the king.
The bride
has been given her price?
She will.
You are witness.
[woman]
Thank you, Lord.
If the betrothed couple
would join me at the alter.
-And join hands.
-Be brief.
May God in his Heaven,
look down with mercy
upon his devoted servants,
Uhtred and Mildrith;
may He bless their union with
love and children and wealth,
and may they in turn,
be sure to give thanks and praise
and live each day
according to His holy word.
-Amen.
Amen.
You are now joined as man
and wife in the eyes of God.
[sniffling]
Tears of joy.
Allow me to help you with that.
Thank you, Lord.
I am a lucky man,
to have such a beautiful wife.
There must have been
many suitors, I'm sure.
You are kind to believe so.
Am I right?
None suitable, Lord.
My name is Uhtred,
call me Uhtred.
Arseling.
Time we were on our way.
Or from time-to-time you may
wish to call me arseling.
Lord...
Danes.
[Mildrith]
Why are we stopping?
Who are they?
Foragers most likely.
But Danes all the same.
Will they attack?
We walk on.
[Mildrith]
They're following us.
[Uhtred]
We walk on. They won't attack.
Then why have you
drawn your sword?
To show them at least
one of them will die.
One or two.
For foragers
they're deep into Wessex.
They're Guthrum's men.
They're a long way
from Lundene.
[door opens]
Lord, the marriage
has taken place.
They are now on the road
to the farmstead.
Good news. Thank you, Odda.
We shall now see how he
responds to the challenge.
Now it is done, Lord,
I do fear for Mildrith.
She will have to
give him the facts.
Oh, he will bark at her,
Odda, I am sure.
But his real anger will be
reserved for you and I.
He will not like being beholden
to God and to king,
but if he is to become
a true Aelderman...
[inhalees deeply]
...he must accept his burden,
that is the test.
Yes, Lord.
Mildrith is his
beautiful consolation.
[chuckles]
Was he struck by her?
He was, Lord.
Why have you
not already married?
You're old enough to have had
two or three children by now.
Lord Arseling, there is a time for
such questions and it has past.
Why has Alfred gifted me
such a beautiful bride?
Has a debt, I'm guessing.
It's not my place
to tell you.
How much?
My father wanted to
find favor with God,
so he devoted a tenth
of his land to the church.
They do not own it, but they
are entitled to its yield;
indeed they demand its yield,
even when crops fail
and Danes raid.
God is good.
So the Bishop
took my father to law.
How much is the debt?
The church is the law,
and the law decreed
that my father
owed to them a huge sum,
quite beyond
his ability to pay.
How much?
He died soon after.
It is a substantial amount,
Lord, it increases yearly.
Alfred could remove the debt,
but he has chosen not to.
The amount owed
is 2,000 shillings, Lord.
[chuckles]
Damn him.
Damn everything he stands for.
Damn his church.
-Damn his God--
-Lord, I must say
-I do not like your blasphemy.
-My name is Uhtred!
Though by all means call me arseling
for not seeing this sooner.
[indistinct chatter in distance]
[Mildrith]
Your new home, Lord.
The land is good but the
buildings are in need of repair.
Look, the families
who live on the land
have come to wish us well.
Send them back to their homes.
They have come to wish us well.
I have known them my whole life.
Lord... Lady.
Oswald manages the farmstead,
he lives nearby.
Welcome home.
And may we offer our
good wishes on your marriage.
Thank you, Oswald, thank you.
And how kind of you all to gather
and to greet me and my Lord, Uhtred.
We have prepared a table,
Lord, for your pleasure.
You have my thanks,
but we're tired.
Of course, Lord.
[chuckles]
Thank you, Oswald, you are kind.
I have a wedding gift,
for each family.
-Tis silver...
-Thank you, Lady Mildrith.
...for your kindness
and your loyalty.
Thank you, so much.
For taking care of the land
in my prolonged absence.
Now there's a welcome sight.
I was expecting there to be
a hall and I find a this.
Pay off your debts
and you can build a hall.
Didn't I tell you
the bastard thinks? Alfred.
If he believes
he can make me beg,
he can think again.
He doesn't want you to beg,
he wants you to obey.
Never.
If you have need for me Lord,
I will be resting.
It seems I am tired.
I am 2,000 shillings in
debt to the church
and you hand out
silver to your tenants.
It is my silver.
You can have what's in my purse.
I don't want
what is in your purse.
Then why scold me?
The stoat;
your farmstead master.
-His name is Oswald.
-He'll need to be watched.
He was trusted by my father.
He lives too well
by the look of him.
I'll make my way to the barn.
You're a guest;
you can sleep in the house.
I prefer the barn. Thank you.
It is your wedding night.
Goodnight lady.
Arseling.
May I leave now?
How many pieces of silver did
you receive, as your price?
Eighteen.
Is that correct?
The price was 33.
I'm sure
it was a honest mistake.
You were robbed.
As I was robbed!
That price is your security
and you will have it, all of it.
May I rest?
Yes.
I am sorry the day has been
a disappointment for you Lord...
...for us both.
[digging sound]
[water sloshes]
You have a good heart,
gifting your silver.
Odda owes you 15 pieces more,
I'll see that he pays.
And the debt's not
something I blame you for.
It's Alfred's deceit.
I should have been wiser.
Though I was blinded by you.
You should eat.
I should eat,
but I don't want to eat alone.
God has made me your wife.
There must be a reason.
God is good.
What is it you are looking at?
There's a scar across the land;
there, the never ending line
of Danes on the march.
Ragnar.
By the time word reaches
Alfred it will be too late.
They would need wings.
Go.
Oswald, what town
lays in that direction?
If they keep going to the west,
in a day or so they'll come
to the fortress, at Werham.
Take your family
and the others to the hills
'til we're sure they've passed.
Do it now.
And the Lady Mildrith?
She travels with me...
to Winchester.
[Oswald] Yes, Lord.
[Leofric]
How many do you see?
The question is
how many will follow?
[Uhtred]
Wessex is being invaded
and we're told to wait
while he prays.
God is his strength, Uhtred.
He needs to be on horseback,
not on his knees.
-I hate this place.
-It grows worse.
Mildrith.
I was not told you were here.
-How pleasing to see you.
-Lord.
And so much of you.
[Uhtred]
Is he ready?
The king is ready,
as is his council.
With me.
You watched 300 men or more
march clean across
Wessex and you did nothing?
I'm here.
A messenger could have been
sent in your place, a boy.
Why did you not
confront these Danes?
You have men. That is your purpose,
to create warriors.
I have been given
barely 20 men and their wives,
most of whom work the fields.
It would have been
a slaughter, Lord.
[Odda the Elder] But you chose
not to fight; we'll never know.
A warrior can only die once!
Why die in vain?
The Danes have traveled from
either Lundene or East Anglia.
Were they not being watched?
We have been watching the ships,
which remain on the Tames.
A mistake.
If Werham is captured,
the ships will follow,
300 men will become 3,000.
My advice is that we march,
without delay.
I don't recall
the King seeking your advice.
Leofric, my trusted man,
how many Danes did you witness?
More than two hundred, by far.
Warriors to a man.
Werham will struggle
to hold them back.
The peace is over.
We have no choice
but to march on Werham
and pray God we arrive
before the fortress falls.
You believe
it is an invasion, Lord?
It could well be the beginning
of the great Dane army, yes.
Council is over. Aeldermen of
Wessex, prepare your men.
Father Beocca!
-I shall pray before we leave.
-Yes, my Lord.
Father. I wish to speak
to the king, privately?
I will ask.
But I note that you are
still to learn respect.
Aelderman Odda,
if I may speak out.
You owe my wife
half of her bride price.
I paid 33 pieces of silver,
she received only 18.
An honest mistake,
she assures me.
Is this true?
Pay him.
Ready the men
to march on Werham.
You should know that Mildrith
is a joy to plough.
You are heathen.
-And you're a virgin.
-No, I'm not.
[door opens]
Yes, he is!
[indistinct chatter]
What is it?
Hmm?
Promise me
you will come back safely.
-Two arms, both ears.
-Promise me.
I'll do my best...
but only if you do the same.
If they come, don't shelter
in a church or nunnery;
go to the hills,
the woods and I'll come...
...for both of you.
[Leofric] Arseling!
Kiss her,
and let's be on our way.
Mildrith, my dear,
I have been looking for you.
My Lady Aelswith!
How good to see you and to
see you looking as you do.
-It refuses to keep still.
-Mine is the same.
Oh, how we suffer.
I pray we both survive;
I pray we four survive.
God will decide.
I have missed you, Mildrith,
and prayed for you each day,
you poor thing.
Why poor?
Living with the man they foisted
onto you, the Pagan.
Having to take his seed
and the like.
Uhtred is decent.
He treats me well... He does.
God will bless your loyalty,
but with luck he will
fall in battle, and soon.
Please, tell me
that you're hungry.
I am... a little.
Meet me in kitchens. I have
arranged a meal for the pregnant.
-But do not rush prayers.
-No, no, of course not.
[door opens, closes]
Oh, Lord, he is not
your most humble
or devout servant,
but I pray, keep him safe.
Let him do your work,
let him see his child.
I was pleased to see
your lady today;
your wife...
and carrying a child.
-Yes.
-It's God's blessing.
It seems like only yesterday,
I was baptizing you as Osbert,
and then again as Uhtred.
What is it you wish
to speak about with the king?
That's between
myself and the king.
He is watching you Uhtred.
-God?
-Alfred...
He's watching how you behave.
He's judging you as a Lord.
He has no right to judge.
He's a king.
He lied to me
regarding the marriage.
Are you referring to the debt?
-You know of it?
-It's not a secret.
And I urge you to show him
you accept it;
especially as it is
owed to the church.
You must remain calm, Uhtred;
respectful.
My Lord.
-I requested a private--
-Have you eaten?
No.
There are times
when I crave meat...
...and other things.
But I know the gratification
would be fleeting;
the suffering prolonged,
and so I suffer gruel.
Though my wife will not allow it to
be called anything other than broth.
You will be happy to learn
that my spies have news.
-From Werham?
-From Ireland.
Ivar, the brother of Ubba,
has been killed there.
Which would be irrelevant
but for the fact
that Ubba wishes
to avenge him, personally.
This is true?
An Irishman across the sea kills
a Dane and the world changes.
The hand of God.
Is this something
Ubba would do, abandon Guthrum?
To avenge his brother, yes, if
guided by his sorcerer's story.
He has a sorcerer?
And...
what does this sorcerer do,
cast spells, perform magic?
He advises, Lord. He looks for omens,
signs, good and bad.
Oh, what nonsense.
What are miracles, Lord,
if not magic?
Miracles are performed by God,
not man.
The Danes would say the same,
that omens are gifts
from the gods.
And they are mistaken.
Who gave the sign
for Ubba to go to Ireland,
was that the hand
of your God? Or theirs?
There is only one God.
Then he must have
spoken to the Danes.
With Ubba now in Ireland;
Guthrum must now decide
whether he will fight alone.
He won't fight alone,
not that he couldn't win.
He will fear losing
too many of his own men?
Yes, Lord.
I am learning that the heathen
cares only for personal gain.
A Dane could never
suffer my gruel.
Broth, Lord.
You are happy,
Aelderman Uhtred, with Mildrith?
Yes, Lord. She's a good wife.
Though, I never would of married her
had I known I' owe 2,000 shillings.
Which increases yearly.
I am told that on your word
the debt can be lifted.
Why should I deny
the church 2,000 shillings?
-I wasn't aware I'd owe it.
-It is not a secret.
Sacrifice and penance are what
separate us from the heathen.
I have my broth,
you have your debt.
Wessex needs an army,
would you agree?
A permanent
and formidable army?
Yes, Lord.
England,
when it finally emerges,
shall need a greater army.
Garrisons of many thousands of men,
all will need feeding, and payment.
It is my intention
that all land owners
shall contribute to the feeding
of this army and its commanders.
And I will need
commanders, Uhtred.
Men like the great
generals of Rome.
Look upon the debt as a gift;
a means of proving your devotion
to Wessex and to England.
If I'd been told the truth from the
outset, Lord, I could've--
You still wear
the amulet, I see.
To remind me of Earl Ragnar.
And why do you not attend
church with your wife?
Why do you not pray to God?
God created everything
that surrounds me:
the fields, rivers, the forest.
The land is my church.
And I pray each day,
Lord, in silence.
-He cannot be tamed.
-But he can be trusted.
I will not
abandon him completely.
He may have a use, I'm sure.
[metal clanging]
Hear me now!
Werham has fallen!
We march at once!
Every man is to be ready
to do as the king asks.
The Danes
have taken the fortress!
Werham has fallen!
We march at once!
We could be slipping in blood and
entrails before the day is out.
With luck.
[indistinct chatter]
Leave him,
there is enough for everyone.
[door opens]
[Young Ragnar]
Guthrum? They're here.
The Saxon army is gathering.
-Is it Alfred?
-Yes.
Is the fortress
repaired and secure?
Yes.
Good. He will not attack.
He doesn't need to.
He knows we will be
hungry within days.
We can raid.
No, he will empty all the grain-stores,
in the surrounding villages.
I have found these church rooms
to be strangely quiet and peaceful.
Lord, I didn't march my men
half way across England
for them to starve.
I shall be on the ramparts.
We came for war Ragnar,
but Ubba has reneged.
To avenge his brother.
You are here.
Should you not be
avenging your father?
When the time is right.
Yes! When the time is right.
We have taken the first steps
against Wessex!
But Ubba has left us weak,
he put all of our of lives at risk.
So until Ubba returns,
we have to make peace.
[grunts]
So if you are there,
God of Rome, strike me down.
I thought not.
We are here to show them
how many we are.
That we are here with God,
and that is our land.
and this is our land.
This is our land, our Wessex.
This is our England!
[crowd murmurs]
And we shall murder any heathen
bastard that tries to take it!
[all cheering]
They wish to talk, Lord.
I know what they want.
They want time.
Odda, with your guards,
you shall go with me.
Leofric, you as well.
And Father Selbix.
Yes, Lord.
Leofric, what do you
make of the fortress?
It looks strong enough, Lord.
No breech,
no signs of lasting damage.
And if we attacked?
We would suffer.
We'd be lucky
to see the inside, Lord.
Good morning, King Alfred.
Guthrum of the Danes.
I too am a king now,
of East Anglia.
You don't need to bow.
I will begin.
I propose a truce.
For any truce to occur,
Earl Guthrum,
you must leave Wessex,
once again.
-And if I refuse?
-We surround you.
Yes, you surround
a small fortress,
but we Danes
surround your entire Kingdom.
That said, I have decided
I shall leave by sea.
Therefore,
I will send for ships.
-How many ships?
-No more than 15.
Very well, your ships have
one month in which to arrive.
Not enough time.
Food and ale for one month only,
or you will
walk back to East Anglia.
Then I will send for 200 ships and
hope they arrive before we starve.
-One month is not enough.
-That is my limit.
You cannot take back
the fortress, you know this.
Food and ale for one month,
no more,
by which time the sea storms
will have arrived, God's storms.
We will be gone within a month,
beginning upon the
delivery of food and ale.
Uhtred, you will come to me
following prayers.
Yes, Lord.
Father Selbix,
you will pray with me.
Yes, Lord.
[Alfred]
Please, sit.
Thank you, Lord.
I have a task for you, Father.
You only have to speak it.
As a guarantee of the peace,
you will be given up
as a hostage; one of ten.
The Danes, too,
will give ten in exchange.
Lord, the Pagans
do not value priests.
You might just as well
offer a hound.
I hear Guthrum
is curious about our faith.
I would like you to become his
teacher; provide instruction.
And if he refuses
to be a student?
Then persist, gently,
with humor, as is your manner.
Make no mistake,
should Guthrum
ever consent to being baptized,
then this war is over;
England is ours.
This would be
truly God's work you do.
Forgive me, Lord, but I cannot
help but feel afraid.
They are not content
to simply kill a priest.
Fear is within all of us...
...as is strength.
[retching]
Lord, I would be
more useful as a warrior,
for when the truce fails.
Oh, the truce will hold,
for a time,
and in that time you will be
my eyes and ears
inside the fortress.
-Listening for what?
-For Ubba.
If and when you hear
of his return, you'll escape.
And if I'm in chains?
Our men here shall disband,
there are fields to work,
but I will build
a beacon on the hill;
you will escape
and light the fire.
Lord, do you know that escape
will be near impossible?
If Ubba returns, the hostages will
be killed and the Danes will attack.
Upon sight of this
first beacon being lit,
other fires will start and the whole
of Wessex will be called to arms.
And if I refuse,
to become a hostage?
Then another man
shall light the beacon.
Why can't you accept me?
I have been
nothing but truthful to you;
why am I always being
put to the test?
Why do you not show your king
the respect that is due?
Because you, Uhtred of Wherever,
you do not see me as your king!
You do not see
my God as your God!
Lord?
I have not finished
with you yet!
Guthrum is waiting to hear
of Ubba's return from Ireland.
I need to know when this occurs,
sooner rather than later.
You... are the only man
who could possibly provide
this information sooner.
Yes, it is possible that you will die,
but it is likely that we shall all... die.
You will go to the Danes.
How you go, as a Saxon hostage or a
Viking warrior, becomes your choice.
I'll do as you ask.
But if my child is born
while I am captive,
I ask that you send word.
Of course,
and should you die as a captive,
rest assured the debt
shall die with you.
Will they treat us well?
You are one of them.
If I am one of them,
then why am I a hostage?
They'll treat us well,
for as long as the truce holds.
If it fails?
They will kill us all,
starting with the priest.
[chuckle]
I have made my peace.
I am ready.
Good evening,
and God bless you all.
Poor wretches.
And, us, Father, what are we?
We are fortunate, Lord.
We know God.
Although granted,
I'm in no hurry to meet him.
Let us pray he feels the same.
Amen.
[indistinct yelling]
Is this rabble
what so many are afraid of?
They are like children!
Enough. Enough!
They're our guests,
for a while.
There's one rule only:
At nightfall, you will gather
and sleep at the church;
the doors will be barred.
At daybreak,
you will then free
to walk, talk, jump,
hump, carry weapons.
My men have orders
not to kill you...
...unless you deserve
to be killed.
I am Guthrum.. and one day
I shall be your king.
Do you understand
what I have said?
You will all say, "Yes, Lord."
[all]
Yes, Lord.
I did not hear you.
I understand you, Lord.
Maybe I will make
a present of you to Ubba.
Should he ever return
from Ireland.
He may not, that's possible.
But then his men
will become my men,
and I will honor him
by killing you myself.
With arrows, perhaps.
-Ragnar Ragnarson!
-Here.
You know this one well;
keep him out of my sight.
Take them to the church;
feed them.
Now you are where you belong.
Now I'm with my brother.
I will remind you
what it is like
to be a Dane
and make you stay.
Brida is here.
I dream about you, vixen.
I'm not surprised to hear it.
You've grown up.
[chuckles]
You should know
I'm with Ragnar now.
He's my man.
That's good.
You should know
that I'm married.
Married! You have grown up!
-He is married?
-Yes, he is married!
Time is moving quicker
than I thought;
tonight we get drunk, we must!
I need to be inside the church.
No, tonight we get drunk,
I'll take you to the church myself,
or we sleep where we fall.
And...
we must talk of the future.
[cheering]
[men grunting]
We are oarsmen!
Pull! Pull!
Uhtred, pull for me.
I need to piss.
I'll return later.
Ragnar, Ragnar!
[all laughing]
I haven't laughed
so much in a long time.
Then you haven't been living.
Or as Ravn would say,
"Tomorrow we die."
When did he ever say that?
When you were out chopping wood.
Oh...
Well, I actually
do need to piss.
What you need to do
is to stop drinking.
Tomorrow we die!
-He's happy to see you.
-I've missed him.
I miss you both.
Are you his wife?
I'm with him.
-Is she beautiful?
-Hmm...
Her name is Mildrith.
Yes, she is beautiful.
She carries my child.
Who decided you should marry?
Alfred.
I have the land I asked for,
in Wessex.
You swear an oath to Alfred.
You marry for Alfred.
You have land
given to you by Alfred.
Your wife carries your child,
and yet you are given up
as a hostage by Alfred?
Are you a spy, Uhtred?
The first sign of Ubba
returning, I am to escape.
But I know
that when Ubba returns
the hostages will be killed.
[scoffs]
Alfred's not fond of me.
Refuse him.
refuse to be a hostage, join us.
I should ask you, Uhtred,
not that it matters,
but I should ask.
Is it a problem to you
that Brida is with me now?
[laughs]
No, I'm happy about it.
I swear.
Alright.
Not that she cares
what you think.
I would hump her regardless.
[grunts]
With affection.
-And with my permission.
-I know.
Do you know Uhtred's
to be a father?
A father... When?
Soon, I am told.
You would want to see it.
Yes, I hope to return
to my wife and child.
Ragnar, I'll be with you
to avenge our father.
Kjartan will pay.
You should have joined me
months ago, with Brida.
I'd sworn an oath.
To a poxy Saxon king!
Ubba wanted to see me dead,
there was nowhere else to go.
You know, I have thought about
that night in the woods.
You had the choice to be
a Saxon or a Dane.
No, no I had sworn an oath.
You should have joined me.
I'll be with you
to kill Kjartan.
I will take you to the church.
To your bed.
[Mildrith screaming, panting]
[grunts]
[baby crying]
-What is it?
-It's a son, lady.
A handsome boy.
You will be Uhtred,
son of Uhtred.
Good morning, Uhtred.
Morning, Father.
Raining again.
One day seems like the next.
[yawns]
It does.
Still, at least,
we're alive to feel it.
How are your
conversations with Guthrum?
Is he a Christian yet?
I believe that time is near, I do.
I often leave him to contemplate alone,
in church.
Guthrum likes to contemplate
war and kingdoms.
The kingdom of Heaven is his
to share, I have told him.
A man can change, Uhtred.
Onward.
God Bless you.
May you enjoy a good day.
Thank you, Father.
He is the king of kings,
capable of great,
great things.
-Such as what?
-Such as miracles.
[chuckles]
Miracles!
Such as what?
Such as... you, Lord.
You are a miracle.
He has made you strong,
yet merciful.
He has... made you proud,
yet humble.
He has made you eager to learn.
He has given you free will,
hoping that you will
find the courage
to choose him above all else.
And, I believe,
I truly believe,
he will been rewarded.
[gate opens]
-I have a message for Guthrum.
-He's in the church.
Lord, may I speak?
Freely.
Ubba and his army
have returned from Ireland.
They are coming ashore
north of here, at the Severn.
And my fleet is where?
They left Lundene several days
ago and are nearly here, Lord.
Every last ship will be here,
every man will be with you.
That is good news.
[groans]
I dispatch you to your heaven.
No need to thank me.
Father...
Ubba has returned.
Did they say?
[weakly] Yes.
[Guthrum]
Men, the peace is over.
Prepare for battle.
[men cheering]
The Saxon hostages,
kill them all.
[grunting and groaning]
Catch him!
Cut him to pieces!
[yelling]
[screams]
Leave him! I say leave him!
Ragnar, please, step aside.
You know all the hostages
have to die.
[Young Ragnar]
Then kill him!
You're welcome to kill him,
but you have to kill me first.
I could've happily
managed without this.
He's a Saxon.
He's a traitor. He's an enemy.
Well, to get to him,
you have to kill me.
My men,
they will not follow you.
I will give you one last charity.
Release him, without a horse.
Are you alright?
I have no words.
You should go.
Go and see your child.
Go.
Yes.
I'll be with you.
Both of you.